RYAN TAN

Mobile: 8111-2210 | Email: kangkhen182@gmail.com
LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-tan-0b5b4b193/ |
Digital Portfolio: https://kangkhen182.wixsite.com/portfolio

PROFILE

I am Ryan Tan and I am a student currently studying in Nanyang Polytechnic School of Information Technology. As someone who likes to brainstorm many ideas, I enjoy coming up with creative ideas and solutions to solve real-world problems, while having interests in artificial intelligence as well. Additionally, I also have experience in communication as I often talk and share my ideas with my teammates and ensure that work has been done as a team leader. From this, I would love to push outside my comfort zone and meet new people and work on projects that can prove beneficial for the company.

EXPERIENCE

SEP 2021- FEB 2022

DEVELOPER INTERN, ELXR

- In charge of Frontend Development work, implementing newly created features onto company's mobile app and website, with one of the works available to view at (https://the-elxr.com/centralsports)
- In charge of IT operational work as well, such as generating weekly and monthly reports for clients, and handling requests from Singapore Sports Hub, our company's main client
- Also help to support backend development work, where we create and develop new features, and create unit tests to ensure that it is working for frontend developers to use.
- Also helped to prepare and participate in face-to-face events organized by ELXR

DEC 2018- MAR 2019

KITCHEN STAFF, PIZZA HUT

- Making the crust and preparing the pizza in order by following the ingredients list to ensure the high quality of pizzas for the customers
- Taking orders of customers and helping with customer enquiries to solve their issues and making them satisfied with our service.

EDUCATION

2019 - CURRENT

DIPLOMA OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, NANYANG POLYTECHNIC

2015-2018

GCE 'O' LEVEL, JURONGVILLE SECONDARY SCHOOL

L1R5- 21 L1R4 – 16

SKILLS

Languages

- English
- Chinese

Other Skills

- UX Design
- Software Engineering
- Data Structures & Admin
- Information Security
- Machine Learning
- Frontend Development
- Artificial Intelligence

Programming Skills

- Python
- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
 - ExpressJS
 - VueJS
 - AngularJS
- ASP.NET C#
- Kotlin
- Flutter
- Ruby on Rails

Database

- MySQL
- PostGreSQL

Strengths

- Strong in programming
- Capable of being a leader
- Able to tackle problems with creative solutions
- Encourage team on standardization of work
- Ability to work in a group
- Able to develop AI models
- Able to develop Frontend applications, website and mobile

ACHIEVEMENTS

NANYANG POLYTECHNIC

- Director's List for 2021/2022 Semester 1
- NYP AI Summer Camp 2020 Kaggle Competition Certificate of Participation
- PolyFintech Hackathon 2021 Certificate of Participation
- Splash Awards 2021 Certificate of Participation

JURONGVILLE SECONDARY SCHOOL

- Jurongville Colours Award, 2018
- EAGLES Award, 2018
- Good Progress Award, 2017
- Chinese Orchestra SYF Certificate of Accomplishment, 2015 & 2017

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITES

NANYANG POLYTECHNIC

- Attended the NYP AI Summer Camp 2020 Kaggle Competition
- Attended the Camp Next Generation by NYP SIT, 2019
- NYP AI Interest Group (Member)
- NYP Google Developers Student Club (Member)

JURONGVILLE SECONDARY SCHOOL

- Chinese Orchestra (Sectional Leader), 2017-2018
- Chinese Orchestra (Member),2015-2016
- Advanced Elective Module Republic Polytechnic Creating Fun Gadgets with Electronics, 2018

HOBBIES

- Video Games
- Cybersecurity
- Reading
- Artificial Intelligence
- Programming